Guide to the Nell Irvin Painter Papers, 1793-2021 and undated, bulk 1876-2007 RL.00990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Service Series, 1963, 1972-2007 and undated, 40 boxes
  - Organizations Subseries, 1963, 1972-2007 and undated, 31 boxes
    - Organization of American Historians (OAH), 1976-1999
      - 1978-1979, Scheduled panels
        - What Did You Do Before You Were Secretary of State? Corporation Lawyers and American Foreign Policy (Box 196)
        - Worker Militancy and the Changing Character of Factory Life, 1933-1946 (Box 196)
      - 1978-1986 and undated, Committee correspondence, 3 folders (Box 196)
      - 1983-1986, Chronological files, 6 folders (Box 196)
      - 1986 Dec. 5, Executive board meeting, National Commission for Social Studies (Box 197)
      - 1986, Minority Historians Questionnaire
        - Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 197)
        - Responses
          - No minorities, 8 folders (Box 197)
          - Some minorities (Box 197)
          - Some minorities (Northeast, South, Midwest, West), 5 folders (Box 198)
          - Individuals' responses (Box 198)
          - Notes (Box 198)
      - 1987, Report of the Ad-hoc Committee on Minority Historians (Box 198)
      - 1992, The Journal of American Historians (Box 198)
      - 1994, Annual meeting (Box 198)
      - 1994-1995, Avery O. Craven Award (Box 198)
      - 1994-1996, Program committee, 2 folders (Box 199)
      - 1995-1996, Chronological files (Box 199)
      - 1999 Apr. 23-25, Conference (Box 199)
      - 2002-2004, Newsletter, donation (Box 199)
      - 2003, Journal of American History, notification of selection as president, 2005 (Box 264)
      - 2004, Notes (Box 264)
      - 2006, Notes and reports (Box 264)
    - unspecified (Box 199)
    - PEN American Center and National Writers Union, 1994-1997 (Box 199)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, Emerson Awards, 1998-2000, 5 Folders (Box 199)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, Book Awards, undated (Box 199)
    - Protect Historic America, 1994, 2 folders (Box 200)
    - SAGE, A Scholarly Journal on Black Women, 1994-1995 (Box 200)
    - Schlesinger Library and the Bunting Institute, Radcliffe College (Cambridge, Mass.), 1992-2003, 3 folders (Box 200)
    - Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, 1990-2000, 7 folders (Box 200)
    - SIGNS: Journal of Women in Culture and Society, 1988-2000, 5 folders (Box 201)
    - Social Research, 1998 (Box 201)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1977-1978 (Box 201)
    - Society of American Historians, 1994-1997 (Box 201)
    - Society of American Historians, Francis Parkman Prize, 1993-1994, 4 folders (Box 201)
    - Sojourner Truth Institute of Battle Creek, 1997-1998 (Box 201)
    - Southeastern Women's Studies Association, annual conference, 1988 Feb. 26-28 (Box 201)
    - Southern Association for Women Historians, 1985, 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 201)
    - Southern Historical Association (SHA), 1975-1997
      - 1975, Annual meeting (Box 201)
      - 1987, Hogan Jazz Archive, Tulane University (Box 201)
      - 1987, Annual meeting, New Orleans (Box 201)
      - 1989, lifetime membership (Box 264)
      - 1992, The Martin Luther King, Jr. Papers Project (Box 201)
      - 1994, Annual meeting, Louisville, 2 folders (Box 201)
      - 1995, Annual Meeting, New Orleans (Box 202)
      - 1995-1997, Executive Council, 4 Folders (Box 202)
    - Southern Regional Council, 1986-1988, 4 folders (Box 202)
    - Southern Review, 1988 (Box 202)
    - Triangle universities security seminar, (UNC, Duke, NCSU), 1988 Apr. 15-16 (Box 202)
    - United States Information Agency (USIA), 1988 (Box 202)
    - University of Alabama. Institute of Higher Education Research and Services Progress Report, 1974-1975 (Box 202)
    - University of North Carolina (UNC) Press
      - 1986-1989, Iris Hill, Folder 1 of 5 (Box 202)
      - 1986-1989, Iris Hill, Folders 2-5 of 5 (Box 203)
      - 1987-1988, Women's studies (Box 203)
      - 1987-2002, Chronological files, Folders 1-6 of 16 (Box 203)
      - 1987-2002, Chronological files, Folders 7-16 of 16 (Box 204)
      - 1989, Robert Griswold's prospectus (Box 205)
      - 1993, Mississippi's Inner Civil War, prospectus (Box 205)
      - 2000, Southern History Across the Color Line: Essays by Nell Painter (Box 205)
      - 2000, Gender and American Culture (Box 205)
    - University of South Carolina, Institute for Southern Studies, Southern Classics Series Editorial Advisory Board, 1995-1997, 3 folders (Box 205)
    - USA Project, minutes from the advisory board meeting of Sept. 26, 1983 (Box 205)
    - U.S. Civil War Center, 1996 and undated (Box 205)
    - Various organizations
      - Annual reports, 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box 205)
      - Awards and prizes, 1984-1998, 2 Folders (Box 205)
      - Memoranda, newsletters, and printed material, 1972-2000, Folders 1-3 of 8 (Box 205)
      - Memoranda, newsletters, and printed material, 1972-2000, Folders 4-8 of 8 (Box 206)
    - WGBH, Advisory Board for An American Place, 1979 (Box 206)
    - White House Millennium Council, 1999 (Box 206)
    - William Greaves Productions, 1995-2000 (Box 206)
    - Women Writing Women's Lives, 1992-1995, Folders 1-3 of 13 (Box 206)
    - Women Writing Women's Lives, 1992-1995, Folders 4-13 of 13 (Box 207)
    - Women's Research and Education Institute, 1995-1997 (Box 208)
    - W. W. Norton, 1996 and undated (Box 208)
  - Engagements Subseries, 1972-2007 and undated, 11 boxes
    Documents relating to Painter's addresses, speeches, and honors at some three hundred conferences, meetings, and symposia over the course of three decades. Although drafts of some of these presentations appear here, most of the substantive drafts have been placed in the Writings and Research Series. This subseries is more a record of what topics she spoke on, what occasioned the event, and with what organizations she has interacted throughout her career. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1972, Sept. 29, In Memory of Joseph Strickland, The Memorial Church, Harvard University (Box 208)
    - 1973
      - May 4-5, Radcliffe Symposium: The Black Woman/Myths and Realities (Box 208)
    - 1975
      - Apr. 11, Symposium on Afro-American Writing (Box 208)
      - Apr. 25-27, Black Roots conference and papers (Madison, Wis.) (Box 208)
    - 1976
      - Jan. 21, A Black Interpretation of the Bicentennial, Hollins College (Roanoke, Va.) (Box 208)
      - June, Great Issues: Women in Politics Today: Compromise or Challenge? (Box 208)
      - Oct., Moton Center for Independent Studies (Box 208)
    - 1977
      - Jan. 15, Personality in History: Experiments in History Teaching, Harvard Science Center (Box 208)
    - 1978
      - Apr. 6-7, Second Annual Symposium, Ethnicity in the Great Lakes, University of Nebraska-Lincoln (Box 208)
      - Nov. 5, Interview with Nell Painter and Houston Baker, Philadelphia Inquirer (Box 208)
    - 1979
      - May, NAACP (National Association for the Advancement of Colored People) LDF (Legal, Defense, and Educational Fund, Inc.): 25th Anniversary of Brown vs. Board of Education Commemoration, 2 folders (Box 208)
    - 1981
      - Feb. 18, Black Survival in the 80's: Looking Backward, or Lessons From History (Jacksonville, Fla.) (Box 208)
    - 1982 Apr. 26, The Impact of Double Standards on Our Society, AFL-CIO Civil Rights Institute (Box 208)
    - 1983
      - Jan. 14, Fifth Annual Martin Luther King, Jr. Memorial Ceremony, Chapel Hill (Box 208)
      - Oct. 3, The Fourth Annual Lorraine A. Williams Scholarship Awards Program, Washington, D.C. (Box 208)
      - Nov. 17, Martin Delany and Reconstruction in the Nineteenth Century (Box 208)
      - Nov. 26, The Role of Black Women in the Civil Rights Struggle and Beyond: A Consultation (Box 208)
    - 1984
      - Apr. 12-14, German-American Symposium, Southern Black Industrial Workers in the Twentieth Century, Baltimore, Md. (Box 208)
      - Apr. 26, Chiaroscuro Colloquium: Jubilee Dreams Deferred, Tenth Annual W.E.B. DuBois Symposium (Box 208)
    - 1985 (Box 209)
      - Jan.-Apr., Statue of Liberty, Ellis Island Centennial, 2 folders (Box 209)
      - Apr. 22, Margaret Olivia (Mrs. Russell] Sage, Diamond Anniversary: Women Contributors to North Carolina Central University (Box 209)
      - Oct. 10-11, Two Hundred Years of Georgia and the South: A Symposium (Athens, Ga.) (Box 209)
      - Nov. 29-30, Maison des Sciences de l'Homme (Paris) (Box 209)
    - 1986
      - Jan.-1987 Summer, National Endowment for the Humanities, summer seminars for college teachers (Box 209)
      - Mar. 4, Writing the Narrative of Hosea Hudson, Columbia Oral History Program (Box 209)
      - Mar. 14, Women's History Through Poetry: An International Conference (New York, N.Y.) (Box 209)
      - Mar. 20, American Studies Seminar, Columbia University (Box 209)
      - May 3, The Challenges of Writing Working Class Biography (New York, N.Y.) (Box 209)
      - July 14, The Concept of Freedom in Afro-American Life, New York Public Library (Box 209)
      - Oct. 23-25, In the Shadow of the Statue of Liberty: U.S.A. 1886 (Paris), 3 folders (Box 209)
    - 1987
      - June 24-28, National Women's Studies Association Conference (Atlanta, Ga.) (Box 209)
      - Sept. 24-26, University of Mississippi visit and lecture (Box 209)
      - Oct. 8, Teaching and Writing Afro-American History Symposium, Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History Meeting (Durham, N.C.) (Box 209)
      - Nov. 23, American Studies Association Meeting, Varieties of American Socialism Session (New York, N.Y.) (Box 209)
      - Black Culture: What it is (Box 209)
      - The Great Depression: America Comes of Age, 1929-1941 (Box 209)
    - 1988 (Box 210)
      - Jan. 15, Field to Factory: Afro-American Migration 1915-1940, Carnegie Mellon University, 2 folders (Box 210)
      - Jan. 28, Women's Studies 50: Panel Discussion on Education and Socialization into the Sex/Gender System (Box 210)
      - May 1, Interview, Hiring Black Faculty a Struggle, News and Observer (Box 210)
      - Sept. 22-24, Tenth Mid-America Conference, University of Kansas (Box 210)
      - Mar. 6-11, Woodrow Wilson Visiting Black Scholar, Lincoln University, 2 folders (Box 210)
      - Aug., Emancipation Conference (Pittsburgh, Pa.) (Box 210)
    - 1989
      - Jan. 21, Harvard and Radcliffe Alumni/ae Against Apartheid, 2 folders (Box 210)
      - Apr. 7, DePauw Conference on Leadership in the 21st Century (Box 210)
      - Apr. 15, Turning the World Upside Down: the Anti-Slavery Conventions of American Women, 1837-1839, The Library Company of Philadelphia (Box 210)
      - June 23, The Age of Booker T. Washington: A Conference in Honor of Louis Harlan, University of Maryland at College Park (Box 210)
      - Nov. 9, Eric Foner's Reconstruction: America's Unfinished Revolution panel discussion, Southern Historical Association Meeting (Lexington, Ky.) (Box 210)
    - 1989-1990
      - All engagements (Box 210)
    - 1990
      - Feb. 7, The Fourth Annual John Hope Franklin Distinguished Lecture, Adelphi University (Garden City, N.Y.) (Box 210)
      - Mar. 26, Private Lives/Public Roles: a Symposium on North Carolina Women's History (Raleigh, N.C.) (Box 210)
      - May 3, "The Puzzle of Sojourner Truth," Lecture to Undergraduate Mellon Fellows, Princeton University (Box 210)
      - Oct. 23, Presbyterian College Southern Culture Series (Box 210)
      - Nov. 7, Lily and Linda Brent: Two 'Doras' of the 19th Century, UCLA Department of History (Box 210)
      - Nov. 18, In Search of Sojourner Truth, The John Hopkins Medical Institutions (Box 210)
    - 1991
      - Jan. 26-30, Lily and 'Linda Brent': Two 'Doras' of the Nineteenth-Century South, Stanford University (Box 210)
      - Feb. 16, Shaw Symposium on Women in Slavery and Reconstruction, Bryn Mawr College (Box 210)
      - Nov. 8, City College Langston Hughes Festival (Box 210)
      - Nov. 13, Critical Matrix editorial board, meeting minutes (Box 210)
    - 1992
      - Dec. 17, Writing History: Works and Progress, The New York Historical Society (Box 210)
    - 1993
      - Feb. 4, University of Connecticut, Institute for African-American Studies (Box 210)
      - Feb. 4, How Do We Know What We Know of Sojourner Truth? Wesleyan University (Box 210)
      - Feb. 20, The Marion Thompson Wright Lecture, Rutgers University (Box 210)
      - Feb., Ohio University (Box 210)
      - Mar. 23-25, 7th National Conference on Undergraduate Research, University of Utah (Box 210)
      - Apr. 5-6, Edmonson Historical Lectures, Baylor University (Waco, Tex.), 3 folders (Box 210)
      - May 11, Trenton YWCA "In Celebration of Women" Keynote Speaker (Trenton, N.J.) (Box 210)
      - Sept. 16, Sojourner Truth and the Methodists, Drew University (Madison, N.J.) (Box 211)
      - Sept. 20, Women and Society seminar, Columbia University (Box 211)
      - Oct. 26, The Ethics of Biography, New York University Biography Seminar (Box 211)
      - Oct., Climbing Jacob's Ladder: the Rise of Black Churches in Eastern American Cities, Museums at Stony Brook (N.Y.) (Box 211)
      - Nov. 11, Representing Sojourner Truth, Rider College (Lawrenceville, N.J.) (Box 211)
      - Nov. 11, Weiss Lecture, Wesleyan University (Box 211)
    - 1993-1994, Correspondence re: lectures and talks (Box 211)
    - 1994
      - Black Women in the Academy conference and publication, "Defending Our Name: 1894-1994," Jan. 13-15 (Box 211)
      - Jan. 24, Tenth Year Celebration of the Sojourner Truth Lecture, Harvey Mudd College (Claremont, Calif.) (Box 211)
      - Feb., Race, Ethnicity and Culture: Constructing African-American Identities and Institutions, United States General Accounting Office (Philadelphia, Pa.) (Box 211)
      - Mar. 3, Organization of American Historians lecture, University of Missouri (Columbia, Mo.) (Box 211)
      - Apr. 7, Hunter College Wistarians Alumni Lecture, Representing Sojourner Truth (Box 211)
      - Apr. 7-8, The Early Psychoanalytic Case: Patients and Narratives, Shelby Cullom Davis Center for Historical Studies, Princeton University (Box 211)
      - May 6, Construction Site: a Colloquium on Walter Benjamin, Princeton University (Box 211)
      - May, Correspondence on Women of Hope study guide (Box 211)
      - Sept., Exodusters: African-Americans in Kansas, in History and Memory, Duke University (Box 211)
      - Sept. 22-23, The Campus Challenge: Lessons in Diversity, Memphis, Tenn. (Box 211)
      - Sept. 24, Trenton Human Relations Commission Oral History Project: Trenton: We've Come Too Far (Box 211)
      - Oct. 1, Human Rights and African-American Religious History: A Conference in Honor of Preston N. Williams (Box 211)
      - Oct. 15, Pennsylvania Women's Press Association fall seminar (Box 211)
      - Oct. 22, Association of Black Princeton Alumni Annual Meeting (Box 211)
      - Nov., Civil War Journal: Women at War, Freedom's Road (Box 211)
      - Birmingham Historical Society (Box 211)
    - 1994-1995 Correspondence on various lectures (Box 211)
    - 1995
      - Feb. 14, Black History Month Fireside Reading (Box 211)
      - Mar., Offer and acceptance for "Rethinking the African American Experience Through History and Literature," proposed NEH Summer Seminar, 1996 or 1997 (Box 211)
      - Mar. 3, Soul Murder and Slavery: The Traffic in Women, University of Kentucky (Box 211)
      - Mar. 23, Sojourner Truth's Moment as Pentecostal and Witch, Marshall University (Box 212)
      - Apr. 6, Frederick Douglass and Sojourner Truth: Different Ways of Knowing, Millersville University (Box 212)
      - Apr. 14, Taylor Lecture, Soul Murder and Slavery, Southwest Texas State University (Box 212)
      - Apr. 20, Carter G. Woodson Lecture, Sojourner Truth's Religion in Her Moment of Pentecostalism and Witchcraft, St. Mary's College (Box 212)
      - Jun. 7, Black Women and Sexuality Seminar, New York University (Box 212)
      - Aug. 27-Sept. 3, 18th International Congress of Historical Sciences (Montreal, Canada), 5 Folders (Box 212)
      - Sept. 28, Barnard College (Box 212)
      - Sept.-Oct., InVision Communications--narration for The U.S. History Video Collection (Box 212)
      - Oct. 6, National Council for History Education, Inc. Conference (Box 212)
      - Oct. 13-14, American Political History: A Symposium in Honor of Vincent P. DeSantis, University of Notre Dame (Notre Dame, Ind.) (Box 212)
      - Oct. 13 and 14, University of Michigan's Tanner Lecture Program (Box 212)
      - Nov. 17, Seminar in African-American Studies, Princeton University (Box 212)
      - The Organization Us Thirtieth Anniversary (Box 212)
    - 1996
      - Jan. 17, Sojourner Truth and Woman Suffrage, Iowa State University, 2 Folders (Box 212)
      - Jan. 18, Sojourner Truth as Itinerant Preacher, l'Université Paris (Box 212)
      - Jan. 26, English Speaking Union Luard Scholarship Committee Annual Meeting (Box 213)
      - Feb. 1, Lecture on Women's History, Rutgers University (Box 213)
      - Feb. 8, Has Affirmative Action Served Its Purpose? Mercer County Community College (canceled) (Box 213)
      - Feb. 9-10, Symposium on Black Women's Studies, University of Kansas (Box 213)
      - Feb. 27, Herbert G. Gutman Memorial Lecture, City University of New York (Box 213)
      - Mar. 12, The Principals Center (Box 213)
      - Mar. 14, Sojourner Truth: The Life of a Symbol, Trenton State College (Box 213)
      - Mar. 15, Center for the Study of American Religion Symposium, Princeton University (Box 213)
      - Mar. 18, NYU Biography Seminar (Box 213)
      - Apr. 22, Ideafest, University of South Dakota (Box 213)
      - Apr. 25, Inclusive Narratives of American History, Stanford University (Box 213)
      - May 3-5, Intersections: Women's History/Intellectual History, Minary Center, Dartmouth College (Box 213)
      - May 5-6, Breaking Boundaries: The Future of American History, Harvard University (Box 213)
      - May 8, Sojourner Truth-The Life of a Symbol State University of New York at New Paltz (Box 213)
      - May 17, Association of Black Admissions and Financial Aid Officers in the Ivy League and Sister Schools 25th Anniversary, Princeton University (Box 213)
      - May 26, Commencement Celebration, Wesleyan University (Box 213)
      - May 27, Talking About Diversity in Scholarly Publishing, American Association of University Presses (Box 213)
      - June7-8, Conference on N.Y. State History, State University of New York College at New Paltz (Box 213)
      - July 26-28, Trauma and Memory: an International Research Conference, University of New Hampshire (Durham, N.H.), Folders 1-2 of 5 (Box 213)
      - July 26-28, Trauma and Memory: an International Research Conference, University of New Hampshire (Durham, N.H.), Folders 3-5 of 5 (Box 213)
      - Sept.-Oct., Publicity tour for Sojourner Truth: A Life, A Symbol (Box 213)
      - Oct. 2-3, Ford Foundation Seminar in Black Women's Studies, University of Wisconsin-Madison, 2 Folders (Box 213)
      - Oct. 25, Plessy vs. Ferguson - 100 Years Later: A North Carolina Perspective, North Carolina Central University Institute for the Study of Minority Issues (Durham, N.C.) (Box 213)
      - Nov.-Dec., New York University Biography Seminar (Box 213)
    - 1996-1998
      - Talks and regrets (Box 213)
    - 1997
      - May 17, State university of New York, New Paltz commencement (Box 264)
      - June 8, Dartmouth commencement (Box 264)
      - June, Nell Painter: Making it in the Academy, interview in Association of American Colleges and Universities newsletter, "On Campus With Women" (Box 214)
      - Sept. 1, C-SPAN Booknotes (Box 214)
      - Sept. 24, Barney Jones Lecture, Duke University (Box 214)
      - Oct. 27-30, Merle Curti Lecture, University of Wisconsin-Madison (Box 214)
      - Oct. 30-31, University of Wisconsin-Green Bay (Box 214)
      - Nov. 20-21, Lectures at the Women's National Book Association and Howard University (Washington, D.C.) (Box 214)
      - New Jersey Humanities Council, Annual Humanities Book Award Competition (Box 214)
    - 1997-1998
      - Talks (Box 214)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 215)
      - DMB Speakers Bureau, Inc. (Box 215)
    - 1998
      - Jan. 31, WGBH Boston interview (Box 215)
      - Jan., Drew University Living Library Dinner (Box 215)
      - Feb.-Mar., Harlem Renaissance Conference, Université Denis Diderot (Paris VII, France) (Box 215)
      - Mar. 4, Black Graduate Caucus Dinner, Princeton University (Box 215)
      - Mar. 8, Sandy Ground Historical Society (Box 215)
      - Mar. 18, Sojourner Truth in Women's History, Seton Hall University (South Orange, N.J.), 2 Folders (Box 215)
      - Mar. 24-25, Sojourner Truth: A Phenomenal Woman, Washington University in St. Louis (Box 215)
      - Apr. 2, The Legacy of Sojourner Truth, Kellogg House (Battle Creek, Mich.) (Box 215)
      - Apr. 2-3, W.K. Kellogg Expert-in-Residence (Battle Creek, Mich.) (Box 215)
      - Apr. 16, Slave Childhood and Soul Murder, New Jersey Historical Society (contains speaking notes and transparencies) (Box 215)
      - Apr. 25, Traveling the Diaspora, Rutgers University (Box 215)
      - Apr. 29, Hunter College High School (New York, N.Y.) (Box 215)
      - May 1-3, Conference on Intersections of American Women's History and American Intellectual History, The Circle (Boston, Mass.) (Box 215)
      - July 16-19, Celebrate '98: Celebrating the 150th Anniversary of the First Women's Rights Convention, Women's Rights National Historical Park (Seneca Falls, N.Y.) (Box 215)
      - Sept. 21, Interview about Sojourner Truth, with Lynn Spangler (State University of New York, New Paltz; interview filmed at Princeton) (Box 215)
      - Oct. 2, African-American History and the Meaning of African-American Biography, Conversations in African-American Studies, Columbia University (Box 215)
      - Nov. 5, Whiteness and Beauty, Old Dominion University (Norfolk, Va.) (Box 215)
      - Nov. 19, Honest Abe and Uncle Tom, Gettysburg College Robert Fortenbaugh Memorial Lecture (Box 215)
    - 1998-1999
      - Meetings, talks, and conferences (Box 215)
    - 1998-1999
      - Nov. 19, Honest Abe and Uncle Tom, Fortenbaugh Lecture, Gettysburg College, Folders 1-2 of 5 (Box 215)
      - Nov. 19, Honest Abe and Uncle Tom, Fortenbaugh Lecture, Gettysburg College, Folders 3-5 of 5 (Box 216)
    - 1999
      - Jan. 18, What We Need to Do Now to Further the Ideals of Martin Luther King Jr., Princeton University (Box 216)
      - Jan. 28, The Civil War: Its Fascination for Us Today, Panel discussion, 92nd Street Y, (New York, N.Y.) (Box 216)
      - Feb. 17, Sojourner Truth, A Life, A Symbol, In Celebration of Black History Month, Boston College (Box 216)
      - Mar. 4, Sojourner Truth and Frederick Douglass, Indiana University (Box 216)
      - Mar. 18-20, Slaves/Slavery in the American Imaginary, Oklahoma Scholar - Leadership Enrichment Program, University of Oklahoma, 2 Folders (Box 216)
      - Mar. 24-27, Retirement dinner for Professor Martin Kilson (Box 216)
      - Apr. 21-22, Sojourner Truth Visits Abraham Lincoln, Lecture, Clarion University (Clarion, Pa.) (Box 216)
      - Apr. 29, Sojourner Truth, American Literature, Long Island University (Box 216)
      - May 21-22, Democracy, Diversity, and the Disciplines: An Invitational Conference, The College Board and the Woodrow Wilson Foundation (Box 216)
      - Jun. 24-27, Black Women in the Academy II, Howard University (Washington D.C.) (Box 216)
      - Summer, The Department Chair: A Newsletter for Academic Administrators (Box 216)
      - Sept. 13, C-SPAN's Historians' Survey of Presidential Leadership (Box 216)
      - Sept. 25, Greenwood Interview (Box 216)
      - Oct., American Studies Association, Canadian Association of American Studies Conference, Montreal (Box 216)
      - Oct. 29-31, Canadian Association of American Studies (Box 216)
    - 2000 (Box 217)